A Guide to the James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1908, 1963-1997
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
The James J. Kilpatrick Papers, 1908, 1963-1997
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6626-s
ca. 450 items (2 Hollinger boxes and 28 bound volumes, 11 linear feet)
This collection consists of James J. Kilpatrick papers, 1908, 1963-1997, including typescripts of newspaper columns, notebooks, and correspondence.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by James J. Kilpatrick on June 8, 1998
Biographical/Historical Information
James Jackson Kilpatrick (1920- ), is former editor of the Richmond News Leader, television commentator, author, and syndicated newspaper columnist.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the additional papers of James J. Kilpatrick, ca. 1908, 1963-1997, including typescripts of his columns, "A Conservative View," "The Writer's Art and Covering the Courts," and "The Writer's Art," bound into volumes. Some of the typescripts have autographs changes and corrections and others are labeled "scanner ready copy."
Other papers include reporter's notebooks, 1978-1994; publication agreement and correspondence with EPM Publications, chiefly regarding his book, The Foxes' Union; correspondence and contract with Universal Press Syndicate concerning a weekly column discussing language, its usage, and the art of writing, and the eventual publication of his columns in book form, including two publicity photographs of Kilpatrick; correspondence with National Geographic Traveler, concerning his travel story, "Richmond on The Noble James," and the typescript of the story; papers pertaining to his participation in the Black-Eyed Pea Society of America; and correspondence with readers concerning his column, "The Writer's Art."
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by subject.
Contents List
- Papers 1908-1994 (Box 1-2)
  - Black-Eyed Pea Society 1908-1990, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - EPM Publications, Inc. 1976-1985, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - National Geographic Traveler article on Richmond by Kilpatrick 1991-1994 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - Universal Press Syndicate 1981-1989, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence concerning The Writer's Art 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Seven Notebooks kept by James J. Kilpatrick ca. 1978-1994, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Bound Volumes 1980-1997 (Box 2)
  - 1. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, scanner ready copy 1980 (Box 2)
  - 2. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, with corrections and notations 1980-1981 Jun (Box 2)
  - 3. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, scanner ready copy 1981 (Box 2)
  - 4. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, with corrections and notations 1981 Jul-1982 (Box 2)
  - 5. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, scanner ready copy 1982 (Box 2)
  - 6. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, with corrections and notations 1983-1984 Jun (Box 2)
  - 7. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, scanner ready copy 1983 (Box 2)
  - 8. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, with corrections and notations 1984 Jul-1985 (Box 2)
  - 9. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, with corrections and notations 1986 (Box 2)
  - 10. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick 1980 (Box 2)
  - 11. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick 1988 (Box 2)
  - 12. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick 1989 (Box 2)
  - 13. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick 1990 (Box 2)
  - 14. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick 1991 (Box 2)
  - 15. A Conservative View by James J. Kilpatrick, scanner ready copy 1992 (Box 2)
  - 16. The Writer's Art by James J. Kilpatrick, with corrections and notations 1981-1985 (Box 2)
  - 17. The Writer's Art by James J. Kilpatrick, scanner ready copy 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - 18. The Writer's Art by James J. Kilpatrick, scanner ready copy 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - 20. The Writer's Art by James J. Kilpatrick 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - 21. The Writer's Art by James J. Kilpatrick 1989-1991 (Box 2)
  - 22. The Writer's Art by James J. Kilpatrick 1989-1991 (Box 2)
  - 23. The Writer's Art by James J. Kilpatrick (date on volume incorrectly reads 1992-1993) 1992 (Box 2)
  - 24. The Writer's Art and Covering the Courts by James J. Kilpatrick 1993 (Box 2)
  - 25. The Writer's Art and Covering the Courts by James J. Kilpatrick 1994 (Box 2)
  - 26. The Writer's Art and Covering the Courts by James J. Kilpatrick 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - 27. The Writer's Art and Covering the Courts by James J. Kilpatrick 1996 (Box 2)
  - 28. The Writer's Art and Covering the Courts by James J. Kilpatrick 1997 (Box 2)